本影音版权属其出版、发行方，字幕制作仅供学术交流之用 请于下载后24小时内删除，并不得有公开传播或作商业盈利之行为 若有违法等相关行为，诸神字幕组恕不承担任何法律或连带责任。
フィーキーさん
Feekiee!
フィーキーさん　フィーキーさん
翻译 koki  放 晴  La Fatalité
Feekiee?
そんな…
This can't be...
He didn't make it in time?
間に合わなかったか？
No, he had plenty of time.
いいえ　時間はあったはずです
Then?
じゃ…
I witnessed Feekiee's state of mind
at the very last second.
最後の瞬間　フィーキーさんの感情が流れ込んできました
压制 暗之亚瑟王  校对 凉YAN Lucifer 时间 Lucifer
Something rattled him,
so he dropped his guard.
何かに動揺して　隙が出てしまったようです
動揺？
Rattled?
I can't believe he'd kill them both to
please that impostor of a mother!
偽者の母親のために　二人も殺されるなんて
Noloty, you mentioned that she appeared
to be too young to be his mother, right?
ノロティ　母親の偽者にしては若すぎだと言ってたが
That's correct. She looked too young
to be Mokkania's mother.
はい　モッカニアさんのお母さんには見えませんでした
そんなことも分からなくなってんですよ
He can't comprehend that anymore!
４年も閉じこっもっている間に　あの人の心はすっかり壊れて…
He's gone insane in the four
years he's been locked...
少し黙っていろ
Stop talking for a minute.
止まる者　愚かなりし
The one who stops is foolish
はらりひらり指に触れた黒い翼の　一片
A piece of black wing gently touches fingers
诸
神&动漫国
君が一つの　物語なら
If you were a story
まだいくらでも　掛け替えられる
You could still rewrite it all you want
血のインクは乾かない
The ink of blood doesn't dry up
誰も知らない　本との僕ら
No one knows the real us
荒れた世界　枯れるのは
What changes the chaotic world
追い求めたのは　ちっぽけな幸福なんかじゃない
What we pursued isn't
Small happiness
戦え　轟く　音を合図に
Fight with a rumbling heartbeat as a sign
意のまま　進めば
What awaits you is infinite if you
move forward as you wish
行く先　果てない
抗え　のたうち
Fight off no matter how many
times you get defeated
幾度と　汚れと
膝を纏った傷跡に夢を
Engrave your dream onto the scar you bear
埋もれそうな今日の記憶繋げるために　明日へ
In order to connect today's memory that's
on the verge of being buried to tomorrow
第9话 弱者
与
Episode 11
A Weakling, the Labyrinth, and Moving the Queen
迷宫
和
皇后的棋步
Mom!
母さん　大丈夫だった？
Are you okay?
I shouldn't have left you alone!
やっぱり母さんを一人にするんじゃなかった
I'm in pain, Mokkania...
苦しいわ　モッカニア
御免　御免　母さん
Sorry! I'm so sorry, Mom!
It's okay... But tell me about that
man. What happened to him?
それより　あの人は…
さっきの人はどうなったの？
あいつは敵だったんだ
He was an enemy.
そんな…　それじゃ…
But that means... you...
Tell me, Mokkania...
ねえ　モッカニア
It's just as Winkeny claimed, right?
ウィンケニーさんが言ってたとおりなのよね？
I was kidnapped by an evil organization,
the Church of Drowning in God's Grace,
私は神溺教団という悪い組織にさらわれて
記憶と視力を奪われた
and my memories and eyesight
were taken from me.
そこを　あなたと同じ　武装司書のウィンケニーさんに助けられた
But then I was rescued by Winkeny,
an Armed Librarian just like you.
そうよね？
That's what happened, isn't it?
うん
ここは神溺教団の隠れ家で
And you're down here...
a secret Church hideout...
あなたは大事な「本」を奪ったハミュッツ＝メセタという人を追っている
pursuing Hamyuts Meseta, the woman who
stole a very important Book of yours.
あなたが殺してしまったのも神溺教団の悪い人たち
The people you killed were bad guys
from the Church, too, right?
そうなのよね？
うん
Yes.
御免なさい　なんでもないわ
I'm sorry. It's okay.
でも　本当に戦わなければならないの？
But do you really have to fight?
Even if they're evil, I'm sure
you can talk things out.
いくら悪い人だからって話しあえば…
This is the only way.
これしか道はないんだ
I see...
そう
やつだ　ハミュッツが来る
It's her. Hamyuts is here.
Stay down, Mom.
母さんは下がって
私が居ては足手まといだわ
When I'm around, I just get in your way.
やっぱりずっと一緒にいるなんて無理だったのよ
That's why I couldn't stay with you.
そんなことない　もう母さんと離れるのはいやだ
Don't say that!
I don't want you to leave me again!
あなたが誰かと戦うのを見るなんて
I can no longer bear to see my son fighting.
母さんは　これ以上…
I'll have the ants lead you
to my room. Wait there.
蟻に案内させる　部屋で待っていて
モッカニア
Mokkania.
If you think you can't win, forget about me.
もし勝てそうになかったら　母さんのことは気にしないで
Don't worry about me.
You must live on.
どんなことがあっても　あなたは生き延びて
分かってるわよねえ　モッカニア
You know already, don't you, Mokkania?
Yes. She's not truly my mother.
ああ　母さんは偽物だ
そうでなくっちゃ
Bingo.
I'm grateful, shadow lurker.
感謝してるわよ　のぞき魔君
Hiza's Book is below, in the
fourth sealed library.
ハイザの「本」は　下の第四封印書庫にあるわよ
I assumed you'd carry Shlamuffen, Hamyuts.
ハミュッツがシュラムッフェンを手にすることも計算のうち
イレイア＝キティとの挟み撃ちさえ避けることができれば
I knew if I could avoid a pincer attack executed
by you and Ireia Kitty, I'd have a chance to win.
勝算はある
Guess I can't get them all with my sword.
次切れないかしらねぇ
一緒に天国へ行くのよ　ウィンケニー
Let us go to Heaven together, Winkeny.
We welcome you with open
arms, Winkeny Bizee.
歓迎するよ　ウィンケニー＝ビゼ君
Welcome to the Church of
Drowning in God's Grace.
神溺教団へようこそ
Mokkania Fluru.
モッカニア＝フルール現在武装司書になるべく訓練を続けている
He's currently training to become
an Armed Librarian.
It's been prophesized that he will,
someday, become a threat to us.
彼は将来我らにとって脅威になるであろうと予言が出た
You will become his mortal enemy.
君は彼の天敵になれ
Ignore the pawns and knights.
Aim only for the queen.
歩兵にも騎兵にも目をくれず　女王だけを殺すのだ
That will be your purpose in life.
君はそれになれ
Work hard and do as the Church instructs.
教団のために立派に働くのですよ
And remember, no matter how far apart
we are, I will always watch over you.
どんなに離れていても母さんは　あなたを見守っていますからね
Okay.
うん
Mokkania Fluru was born in this town.
モッカニア＝フルールはこの街で生まれた
母親は両親の気まぐれて子供を生まされた哀れな女
His mother, poor soul, was impregnated
with him at the liege lord's whim.
They came into a humble existence.
二人は質素な生活を送っていた
僕はモッカニア
I am Mokkania.
In this town, I lived a happy
life with my mother.
僕と母さんはこの街で幸せに暮らしていた
Weak as a child, I was constantly bullied,
小さいころの僕は弱虫で　いつもいじめられていた
but my mother always came to my rescue.
でも　そんなときはよく母さんが助けてくれた
母さんは優しい人だった
She was such a kind woman...
暴力が大嫌いで　いじめっ子を叱ったり
Hating violence, she would scold bullies.
喧嘩してる子たちを注意してくれた
She always reprimanded the neighborhood
kids when they fought.
"Now, now. Play nice."
That was her line.
みんなで仲良くねって　いつも言ってた
だから僕も暴力は嫌いだ
That's why I hate violence myself.
母さんが嫌がることは絶対にしない　そう決めたんだ
I made up my mind that I'd never do
anything my mother would oppose.
But then...
なのに…
I'm back!
ただいま
I don't understand.
分からない
Why did Mokkania decide to become
an Armed Librarian?
モッカニアはなぜ武装司書を目指したのか？
Why did he shut himself away
after the Guinbecs revolt?
なぜ　グインべクスの反乱以来閉じこもっているのか
彼の心はまるで　黒蟻の迷宮だ
It's as if his heart, itself,
has become a labyrinth of black ants.
Be right there.
はい
Will you be staying the night?
お泊りですか？
こちらに必要事項ご記入ください
Please fill out this form.
この町へは観光で？
Are you here on vacation?
人間とはこの世の全ての幸福を得る権利のあるもの
Humans are beings with the right to gain
all the happiness this world may offer.
Oh, you're with the Church.
Why didn't you say so earlier?
あら　教団の方でしたの？
早くおしゃってくださいな
失礼しました　次の指令です
My apologies. Here is the next directive.
レーリア　ヒョウエ　コリオ
Relia, Hyoue, Colio...
And these three will be staying here?
この子たちがここに泊まるのね
母さん
Mom!
ええ？
What?
I'm Winkeny!
俺　ウィンケニー　俺だよ　ウィンケニーだよ
It's me! It's Winkeny!
ウィンケニーさん？
Winkeny? I'm sorry... Have we met?
あの　どこかでお会いしましたっけ？
I get it! Now I get it, Mokkania!
分かった　分かったよ　モッカニア
これが母親を失うということか
This is what losing your mother feels like.
僕はモッカニア　僕は母さんを幸せにしてあげたかった
I'm Mokkania. I wanted to
make my mother happy.
だから武装司書になろうと思った
That's why I decided to become
an Armed Librarian.
I can get lots of money if I become one.
武装司書になればお金がたくさんもらえる
でも　母さんは死んだ
But...
She died.
Even so, I didn't give up.
それでも　僕は諦めなかった
図書館には世界中の「本」が集まるから
All the world's Books are
brought to the Library.
So if I wait long enough,
perhaps I can see her again.
待っていれば　いつか出会えるかもしれないから
ああ　母さん
Mom!
You found Renas Fluru's Book.
I've made her read it countless times.
あなたが発見したレナス＝フルールの「本」を何度も読ませ
暗示と薬の力で記憶を植え付けました
Using drugs and hypnosis,
I've embedded Renas's memories into her.
本物の記憶を持つ偽者
An impostor with real memories...
しかし　やはり若すぎるのでは…
Isn't she too young, though?
俺が選んだ「肉」だ　間違いない　これでいい
I chose this Meat myself.
I'm positive that she's the one.
She's perfect...
モッカニアの母親は　これでいいんだ
She's perfect to play Mokkania's mother.
In all the forest, the ants are
the smallest and weakest.
蟻君たちは森で一等弱くて　小さな生き物です
その蟻君たちが力を合わせて　食べ物を運んでいました
So they all worked together,
to gather food.
"Because we are not strong,
we must help each other."
僕たちには力がないから助け合わなくちゃねぇ
Seeing the ants help each other,
Mr. Fox apologized to Mr. Squirrel.
違う
その常が反省した狐君は　リス君に謝りました
No!
Seeing the ants help each other,
Mr. Fox apologized to Mr. Squirrel.
やめろ　やめろ
Stop.
Seeing the ants help each other,
Mr. Fox apologized to Mr. Squirrel.
Stop!
After he saw the ants himself,
Mr. Bear apologized to Mr. Fox.
蟻君たちを見た熊君もやっぱり狐君に謝ってくれました
And so, together, they were able to
live in the forest happily ever after.
こうして　森のみんなは仲良く暮らせるようになりました
The end.
愛でたし　愛でたし
Mom...
母さん
What are the conditions?
要求はなんだ？
I want Hamyuts Meseta dead.
ハミュッツ＝メセタの命
断ればあの女に秘密をばらす
Refuse, and I'll tell her the truth...
That she's not really Renas.
自分がレナスの偽者だということを
If she learns the truth,
it will fill her with hatred...
それを知ったら　彼女は憎むだろうな
Hatred toward the Church,
for taking her memory.
自分の記憶を奪った神溺教団を
そしてお前を
And hatred toward you.
Me?
僕を？
分からないのか？　モッカニア
Don't you know, Mokkania?
すべてはお前のためにしたことだった
All of this was done for you.
母親と共にいたいのなら　俺に従え
You'll do as I say if you wish
to stay with your mother...
If you want her to continue
being your mother.
彼女に母親のままでいてほしいなら
それとも　もう一度母親を失ってみるか？
Or would you prefer to
lose another mother?
モッカニア
Mokkania...
モッカニアが人を殺した
He killed people...
My little boy, a killer...
あの優しかった子が
A Church hideout?
神溺教団の隠れ家？
But they said this is a library...?
でも　ここは図書館って
Something doesn't add up.
何かおかしい
ウィンケニーさんもあの子も何かを隠している
Winkeny and the boy are hiding something.
あの子は本当にモッカニアなのかしら
Is he really Mokkania?
No... This is wrong! How could I...
違う　恐ろしい　私は　なんて…
杖
My cane...
溺れ死に　ハミュッツ
Drown and die, Hamyuts!
I won...
勝った
母さん
Mom...
母さん　どうしてこんなところに？
Mom?
What are you doing here?
怪我でもしたの？
Are you hurt?
That's...
それは…
まだ　私を母と呼ぶの？
You're still calling me "Mom"?
Isn't this your mother's Book?
これはあなたのお母さんの「本」じゃないの？
でも　私じゃない
But it's not me in here.
This isn't my Book!
これは私の「本」じゃない
誰なの？　モッカニア
Who am I, Mokkania? Who am I?
私は誰なの？
ねえ　答えて　モッカニア
Please tell me... Mokkania!
That's not true...
嘘だ　そんな…
My telepathy isn't reaching
the Acting Director.
代行と「思考共有」　繋がりません
I see. So that's what happened.
そう　そういうことだったの
御免　母さん
I'm sorry, Mom.
母さんに隠しごとするなんて　駄目じゃないの
Hiding things from your mother...
Shame on you!
Look. You're all beat up now.
こんなに傷だらけになって
どうして？
Why?
What?
なにが？
僕を　憎まないの？
You don't hate me?
どうして憎まなきゃいけないの？
Why should I?
Didn't you fight to keep me safe?
私のために戦ってくれたのでしょ？
That displayed your love for me.
あなたはそれでも愛してくれた
The fact you love me hasn't changed.
愛してくれたことに変わりはないわ
Say it. Call me "Mom."
言って　私を母さんと言って
Except for being Renas Fluru,
だって　レナス＝フルールであるほかに
私には何もないの
I've got nothing.
いいわよ　モッカニア
I'm ready for you, Mokkania.
まだ殺し合いましょう
Shall we fight to the death now?
ハミュッツめ　生きていたのか
Hamyuts, you monster... You're still alive?
御免なさい　母さん
I'm sorry, Mom.
なんだ　そうなのモッカニア
Huh? Is that how it's gonna be, Mokkania?
もう終わりなの
Throwing in the towel already?
嘘をついて　人を殺して　本当は嫌だった
I lied, I killed... I hated doing those things.
でも　一緒にいたくて　忘れてた
But in my desire to be with her,
I forgot all of that.
そんな人じゃないのに
She wasn't that kind of person...
そんなことをしても喜ばないのに
She wouldn't approve of my behavior...
あの人と一緒に死にたいんじゃないの？
So don't you want to die alongside her?
それくらいは好きにさせてあげるわよ
I can give you that much.
そう思ってた
I thought about doing that.
お前を殺して
I'd kill you. Then I'd have all the time in
the world to be with her in my room.
あの部屋で　母さんと
１分１秒でも長く
そして…
And then...
But that was just me being selfish.
でも　それは僕のわがままだ
暴力はいけない
Violence is wrong.
強いものが弱いものをいじめてはいけない
The strong shouldn't bully the weak.
あの人を　殺してはいけない
I can't let her die.
Is that all you have to say?
言いたいことはそれだけ？
Tell the others that I'm sorry...
みんなに　すまなかったと
馬鹿な子
What a dumb child.
No. He was happy.
いや　幸せそうだった
レナスと会ったときの彼は本当に幸せそうだった
When he was first reunited with Renas,
he was genuinely happy.
ふん　そっ
Yeah?
It's odd...
なぜだろう？
なぜか　あの顔を見ることができただけで俺は…
Just seeing the look of contentment
on his face made me...
That's it!
そうか　俺はただ
All I ever really wanted was to
reunite Mokkania with his mother.
モッカニアを母親と会わせてやりたかっただけだったんだ
あんたも馬鹿な子ね
You're a dumb child, too.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Acting Director, Hamyuts Meseta.
初めまして　館長代行のハミュッツ＝メセタです
早速ですが　このあたりは大変に危険ですので
Sorry to rush you, but it's
extremely dangerous in here.
I'll escort you outside.
おもてにご案内します
ハミュッツ　女性の方でしたの？
Hamyuts... You're a woman?
手をお貸ししますか？
Shall I hold your hand?
いいえ　自分で歩けます
No. I can walk on my own.
Wait a second, Mokkania.
止まりなさい　モッカニア　見て
Look.
Wow!
Don't step on them.
踏んではいけないわ
Okay.
うん
Small or weak, we're all God's creatures.
小さいものでも　弱い者でも　みんな同じなの
We all cling to life.
The ants, you, me... all of us!
蟻君たちも　モッカニアも　母さんも
みんな一生懸命生きてるの
So, never bully those weaker than yourself,
だから　弱い者をいじめたりしないで
and regardless of what happens,
don't hurt others.
どんなことがあっても　他の誰かを苦しめたりしないで
みんな同じなんだから
Because we're all God's creatures.
忘れないでね　モッカニア
Don't forget that, okay, Mokkania?
うん
Okay.
I'm back, Mom.
ただいま　母さん
Lost the light
Before closing the sun
If it's a sparkling storm
Jump in before it tempts
The end comes to everyone one day
When the day comes
Aim for the future that begins to move
Even if it's already been written
Search and even acquire the
meaning of getting hurt
In order to be myself
The Past,
首筋に親指を埋める
Pressing your thumbs to
the back of the neck...
The Past, Irrationality,
Pressing your thumbs to
the back of the neck...
The Past, Irrationality,
それが愛の証明なら
If that's the proof of love,
果てなき苦痛の呻きさえ
then the groans of sheer pain
过去与无理和烟斗之烟
The Past, Irrationality, and a Pipe's Smoke
then the groans of sheer pain
become soft, masochistic gasps.
焦れた甘い喘ぎに変わる